Prahlad Joshi

User Interface and Experience Designer



+91 82176 25498

Bengaluru



PROFILE OVERVIEW

I am a passionate designer with a strong knowledge and spent 8.7 years practicing the user-centered design process with emphasis on rapid prototyping. A fast learner and a team player. I have experience in Agile and Scrum methodology with multidisciplinary teams and over seeing creative product direction, design and concepts, development and product launch for web and mobile applications.

EXPERIENCE

WONDERBOTZ INDIA PVT LTD

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

Redesigning of the Wonderbotz website wherein my responsibilities include:

Requirement Collection Wireframe/Mock-ups User Experience
Usability Testing Prototypes Project & Team Management

IDEMIA INDIA PVT LTD

APRIL 2019 - OCTOBER 2021

Designing of the AUGMENTED VISION & IBRS ADJUDICATION products wherein my responsibilities include:

Requirement Collection Wireframe/Mock-ups User Experience

Maintained Stylesystem Prototypes Web/App Experiences

Collaborated with Product & Engineering team to design products

KPISOFT TECHNOLOGIES

NOVEMBER 2016 - APRIL 2019

Designing of the company Portfolio website, SKYLARK website and mobile applications wherein responsibilities include:

Requirement Analysis Wireframe/Mock-ups Web/App Experiences

Usability Testing Prototypes Project & Team Management

SAGGEZZA INDIA PVT LTD

APRIL 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2016

Redesigning of INDELUST website wherein my responsibilities include:

Requirements Prototypes Visual Designs Layout Development
Usability Testing Prototypes

ZENTEL TECHNOLOGIES

SEPTEMBER 2015 - APRIL 2016

Designed multiple E-Commerce websites wherein my responsibilities include:

Requirements Prototypes Visual Designs Layout Development
Usability Testing Prototypes Icons Creation

DIGIVERTICAL TECHNOLOGIES

SEPTEMBER 2015 - APRIL 2016

Worked and designed multiple E-Commerce websites wherein my responsibilities include:

Requirements Prototypes Visual Designs Layout Development
Usability Testing Prototypes Icons Creation

EXPERTISE

Product Design
User Interface
User Experience
Wireframing
Mock-ups
Prototyping
Research
Design System

TOOLS

Figma
Framer
InVision
Zeplin
Adobe Illustrator
Balsamiq
Adobe XD

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML
CSS, SCSS
BootStrap
Material Design
WordPress
Magento
Ionic and Angular

OTHER TOOLS

JIRA
Confluence
GitHub
SmartSheets
SourceTree

EDUCATION

Bachelor of
Engineering in
Computer
Science with an
aggregate of
69%

AWARDS

Received best employee of the month in IDEMIA in the year of 2020

Employee of the month in KPISOFT in the year of 2017